In this first Java video, I'll
introduce you to the concept of
variables. In English, we
use the word "variable" like this, and in
Vietnamese, we translate it
as "variable". Here, we'll
run the first example together.
For now, let's not talk
about the code yet. Let's just
copy and paste the example first. We
'll practice later. First, I'll copy
this example. Yes, you can copy it for
me to make it faster. Why do I
ask you to copy? Because sometimes when
you type it, it's wrong. But now,
copying and pasting will prevent errors.
First, I've already opened the "
Hello world" file. This is the same file as
before. We'll paste it here.
Look at the effect of our
previous configuration. For example, if
you accidentally copy and paste and it's
misaligned like this, we press the save button.
After you press the save button,
our code is straight. Haha, it
looks very nice here.  So
we have a few options. Look,
there's an option to run "
Hello world" right here. It's not
necessary to right-click like
this. We don't necessarily need to
right-click like
this. We have the "Run" option like
this. Let's see if it runs.
Let's try clicking here.
There are a few options here. Here,
there's an option here.
So, from now on, you
can click the button above. The "
Run" button is right here. It's not
necessary to right-click and
select "Run as a Java Application".
After you run it, you'll see
the number 15 in the terminal like
this. That means it's successful! The first concept
we need to understand is the
concept of variables in Java.
Here we have variable 'a', variable 'b',
variable 'c'. These are called
variables. Essentially, these are the
variables we use to
store values.  It's just values. Because
our program revolves around the values
of variables, right? Here,
the variables we see
on the screen—the word 'y'
int—is an abbreviation for integer.
That means integer numbers. We
declare three integer variables: variable 'a', variable 'b',
variable 'c', and integer variable 'c'. The
value is equal to a + b, so here we
have 6 + 9 equals 15. That
's why we see '
sam 15' on the screen. First, let's
learn about the rules for
declaring variables. In fact,
for Java, it's different from
many other languages. When learning a
new language, we always follow the
rules of that new language. Don't
apply the mindset of a language
you already know to this one. For
example,
I'm currently coding in JavaScript, for instance,
I'm coding in `t-sut`, which is the
opposite of Java.  Here, I'm
going to forget everything I know and start
learning from scratch in Java. In
Java, we need to declare the
variable 't'. What is 't'?
We'll explore this in more detail in the next
video. Let's just accept
this concept for now. First, we'll
declare the data type, then the
variable name, and finally the
initial value. For example, here you
type 'in a = 6' like this. This
means that the value is of type 'int'. This 'int'
is an
integer type. Next,
we set the variable name to 'a'.
Look, the value type and the variable name
are separated by an equals sign, and
after the equals sign is the value we
assign. So,
our variable name is A, right?
We set the variable name to 'a' and
its value is 6 like this.
Now, let's
test it. Let's go
back here. For example, instead of
you, it's me.  I'll delete everything. I'll type
this. We'll declare
this. For example, here I'll write 'in'.
Ask Genit. Why do we have to type '
in'? What's the point of asking Genit? Let me calculate it
myself. I
'm 26 years old, so I
'll write '26'. So,
first we have a variable called '
int'. We name it 'ask'.
Let's assign the value 26. Please
note that when we code in Java, we
need a semicolon to end a statement.
This is a principle of the language. And
here, there's a warning line, just ignore it.
Here, there's a
warning line on the left.
Ignore it, as long as there's no error.
If you get an error, that's when you should be
worried. But here, there's no
red mark, so it's okay. So,
first, I've successfully declared a
variable, right?  However, it's
not always
necessary to declare a variable and assign a
value to it. Let's take an example.
Here, we'll write something like "print
test", "print test", and semicolon like
this. This variable, "test
", has no value after
we declare it. You
can assign a value instead. You'll see, for example, "test", "
test equals 10", "test", "test equals 10".
This is the second way to
declare a variable. We
declare it first, and then
assign a value to it. It's not always the case that
we declare a variable and
then assign a value. This
is an important point to remember when
declaring a variable. Now, let's
talk a
little about naming conventions. In
fact, when we name variables,
we use
characters called the alphabet, from a to z.
We can write them in lowercase or lowercase.
That we capitalize this dollar sign or
that we use an underscore. Note
that our variable names are
case-sensitive and our variable names
do not start with numbers. We do not
use keywords used to build the
Java language, such as `new`, `class`, `
constant`, etc. Okay, here's
a little exercise for you
guys: if you look at the
list here, can you tell
which variable names are valid and which are
invalid? To know if
our variable names are valid or not, in
reality, when you
code here, when we
declare something, it will immediately throw an error.
For example, here I will write it. I will
use a keyword in the
Java language, the `if` keyword. You can see
that
immediately it will underline the word `if`. You can see that it will immediately underline the word `
invalid
variable declare ID`.
So, we  We encounter errors right from the way
we name variables. For example, writing "
print a" doesn't cause an error, right? But
if we write "print 1A," it will
cause an error because in Java,
variable names cannot start with the
number 1; they must start with a digit.
So, to know
if our variable names are correct, the
simplest way is to
use normal variable names.
We shouldn't use numbers,
special characters, or anything like that.
Using a normal variable name
rarely causes errors, and when it does, the
IDE
will immediately report it. So,
I believe that
if we code with an IDE,
we never have to worry about variable naming. We only need to worry
when coding on paper,
right? Finally, I want to
share with you the
operators we often encounter when
working with code. There are
four main operators: addition, subtraction, multiplication, and
division.  This plus sign, this minus sign, this multiplication
sign is the next sign,
and this slash is the division sign.
Our principle is to perform operations from
left to right. Multiplication and division come
before addition and subtraction.
We
apply mathematics to programming in the same way we do it in math. For
example, here I have a sequence of numbers like
this. I'll copy it
here. Here's
an example: Test equals this.
Test equals... I'll use test equals 5 plus
9 x 3 - 10 divided by 2. What do you think the
result is? Guess! Please
note that we will
follow the principle of
multiplication and division before addition and subtraction, not
from left to
right. It prioritizes multiplication and division
first. So, we have: 9 + 3
is 27, right? 9 + 3 + 27 + 5 is 32. 32
minus 5 equals 27. So here
we have...  The result is 27. To find out
what our result is,
similar to the previous day, please help me type it.
Type the keyword: `system
out`, `control`, `
space`, `enter`. Okay, so it's
giving you a hint.
Here, I'll write it down: `check test`. Don't
worry, for
this `system out` command, we'll learn about it later.
In this video, just type along with me so
our code runs.
Oh, sorry guys, I'm used to coding with
JavaScript. JavaScript uses commas,
but Java uses plus signs
like this. For Java, that's the
correct way.
Even I made a mistake, let alone
you guys! So,
first, I have it. I'll
run it again. I'll run
this, and our check test is
27. This is how
we can perform this calculation. It's
not done from left to
right. Multiplication and division come first, then addition and subtraction, and
then from left to right.  To put it simply,
in this video I've
introduced you to how to
declare a simple variable in Java,
and here we've
learned about the first data type, which is
integers. Don't worry, there are
many other data types, and we
'll learn them in the following videos. In the
next video, I'll guide
you on how to understand
this statement. Because
we want to be able to
apply what we learn,
in the next video we'll
learn about the `systemout` statement.